

ELECTRICAL AND ELECTRONIC ENGINEER · FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Kwaluseni, Matsapha, Opp. University Of Eswatini

■ (+268) 7648 0479 / (+268) 7948 0479 | sfisolindelwa@gmail.com | LindelwaSfiso | lindelwa

"It's not what you achieve, it's what you overcome. That's what defines your career."— Carlton Fisk

Summary _

Recent graduate from the University of Eswatini with a Bachelor's degree in Electrical and Electronics Enginnering, majoring in Telecommunications. Experienced self-taught developer with a focus on web and mobile development, who has built production ready apps and websites.

Personal Profile _____

GENDER Male

Date of BirthFebruary 11, 1999NATIONALITYSwazi

ETHNICITY African
MARITAL STATUS Single

LANGUAGES Siswati, English

Professional Profile _____

- Hard working, ambitious and self-motivated qualified electrical and electronic engineer.
- Reached national level in Huawei Networking Challenge 2021 & 2022.
- Half a decade of web and mobile development experience.
- Participated in an Innovation for Impact Siemens Design challenge (Engineering for change, May 2020).
- Proficiency in the latest programming languages, search engine optimization & web development tools and platforms.

Computational Skills And Competences _____

Programming Languages C/C++, Python, Java, Kotlin, JavaScript, PHP, Matlab, R, LaTeX

Software Packages Microsoft Office suite, Arduino, AutoCAD, Android Studio, Git Databases & OS SQLite, MySQL, Windows 7, 10 & 11, Ubuntu/Linux, Android

Web-Dev. Django, REST API, ReactJS, HTML5/CSS

Strengths Analytical Problem Solving, Hard working, Teamwork and Collaboration, Reliable,

Time management, Meet Deadlines

Work Experience

TOUCH IT (PTY) LTD

Mbabane, Eswatini

March 2021 - May 2021

INTERN, NETWORKING DEPARTMENT

- Network planning, design and maintenance.
- Maintained wireless networks for clients remotely using UniFi from Ubiquiti Networks.
- · Provided on-site assistance to end users pertaining to the installation, troubleshooting, and maintenance of their network devices.
- Monitored Wi-Fi networks using The Dude Network software.
- Configured new devices and performed connectivity tests.

AfriShopOn (PTY) LTD

Kwaluseni, Eswatini

CO-FOUNDER & FULL STACK DEVELOPER

February 2021 — Present

- Designed, implemented and deployed an e-commerce store, utilizing Python for backend, focusing on high-availability, search engine optimization and auto-scaling.
- Implemented a REST API server.
- Designed and developed a mobile application version of the web application.
- Integrated multiple payment gateway methods, including MTN MoMo.

Education

University of Eswatini (UNESWA)

Kwaluseni, Eswatini

BACHELOR OF ELECTRICAL AND ELECTRONIC ENGINEERING

Mar. 2017 – Jan. 2023

- Major: Telecommunications
- CGPA: 5.19/6.00 FIRST CLASS
- Project: Emergency Reporting Mobile Application (App)
- Supervisor: Dr Thembelihle Dlamini

Evelyn Baring High School

Nhlangano, Eswatini

SGCSE / IGCSE

2015 - 2016

Portfolio_____

- My Portfolio can be found here: https://dlamini-lindelwa-portfolio.netlify.app/
- Projects: https://dlamini-lindelwa-portfolio.netlify.app/pages/projects.html
- Some sites require authentication, use **sfisodummy@gmail.com** and **rootroot** as username and password respectively for authentication.

References _____

Dr T. Dlamini (+268) 7844 6556

Lecturer, Department of Electrical and Electronic lihle20@yahoo.com
Engineering, University of Eswatini

Mr. Ncamiso Dlamini (+268) 7621 2417

TEACHER, DEPARTMENT OF SCIENCE AND MATHEMATICS, EVELYN (+268) 7955 5982

BARING HIGH SCHOOL